Lijie Cheng

eden.ljcheng@gmail.com | 0430934999 | Lidcombe, NSW, 2141 www.linkedin.com/in/eden-cheng | https://github.com/chengeden

Summary

- A highly motivated and skilled Full Stack Developer with fully commercial level project experiences in developing user-friendly websites.
- Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and NodeJS.

 Self-managed programmer with a focus on writing readable, reusable, and maintainable code in Agile team.

Technical Skills

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, JavaScript/ES6, Typescript, React, React

Hooks, Redux, React-router-dom, Axios, Styled Components, Next.js,

Responsive design, Flexbox, Bootstrap, Media queries

Back-end: NodeJS, Express, JWT, bcrypt

Test: React testing library, Jest

API: Ajax, RestfulAPI, Swagger

Database: MongoDB, Mongoose

Develops Tools: Jira, Git, Github, Bitbucket, Postman, VScode

Methodologies: Agile

Cloud services: AWS EC2, AWS S3

Working Experience

Intern Full Stack Developer at JR Academy | Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

key Responsibilities:

- Engaged in full stack development utilizing the technology stack, including React, Redux, Typescript, CSS, LESS, NodeJS, keystone, MongoDB and web UI followed with project requirements by Zeplin.
- Developed the resume section in JR Academy website following the new UI design.
- Utilized Jira and Bitbucket for task development and code review
- Participated in daily stand-up meetings.

Achievements:

- Successfully rewrote the resume component from class component to functional component based on new UI design.
- Experienced on working with BA, UI designers, Devops engineers and other developers in an agile environment.

Project Experience

Team Project

Jungle Meet, Team Jungle Meet | Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

- Worked as a frontend developer in an Agile team. Developed a online movie forum
 website to provide customers to look through movies and make discussion. Website -https://www.junglemeetforum.com
- Tech stacks: Typescript, React, NextJS, redux, Styled-component, customize Chakra
 UI, following web UI requirements provided by Figma and Agile Methodologies. Main task:
- Participated in and contributed daily stand-up meetings and sprint planning meetings.
- Fetched movie data from third-party API(TMDB) and display to user-friendly design.
- Created a user friendly interface in the front-end using Nextjs, Typescript, Styledcomponent and Chakra UI, including hero banner, nowplaying and upcoming section in home page.
- Created Nowplaying and All movies page with list movies feature and sort by different conditions using React Hooks and Axios, and Infinite Scroll.
- Responsive design using Media Query
- Used React useMemo hook to get better performance when rendering.
- Managed application states with Redux Toolkit in order to avoid props drilling.
- Utilized Swagger to visualize and interact with our API, making it easy for back-end implementation.
- Worked with Agile workflow on JIRA, managed codes with Git version control, and collaborated coding using Github.
- Performed code review for peers and provided recommendations for improvements.
- Documented new tech skills on Notion and shared the knowledge with team members.

Yabber, The Debugger Team | May 2022 – Aug 2022

- Worked as frontend developer in an Agile team to build a online chat app that aiming to facilitate communication within companies or organizations. Website -https://www.yabbertech.com
- Build features using javascript ES6, react, context, styled components, formik, customize MUI components, font awesome and media query, including:
- Setting page for user profile display and update, and password change with React Hooks, Axios, context and formik
- Team member information card components in about page for display team members with styled components and MUI components
- Responsive design for setting page using media query

Personal Project

Instagram-Clone | Sep 2023 - Present

• Developed a full-stack web application inspired by Instagram, enabling users to create, view, and manage posts and profiles.

Backend:

Built the backend application using Express.js to create a RESTful API.

- Integrated MongoDB for data storage, utilizing Mongoose for schema definitions and database interactions.
- Implemented JWT authentication for secure user login and route protection.
- Developed models for users and posts with fields such as username, email, password, profile pictures, post images, and more.
- Set up a modular route structure, segregating authentication, profiles, and post-related routes.

Frontend:

- Developed the frontend application using React, Redux-toolkit, react-router-dom, styled-components, Material-UI.
- Utilized **Redux** to manage frontend data like user information, user profile and post data.
- Designed a user-friendly interface with components such as Navbar, Home, and Post.
- Implemented a dynamic navbar with features like search and a dropdown menu for userrelated actions.
- Developed the Home component to display stories and posts, enhancing user interaction.
- Utilized React Router for seamless navigation between different components and views.
- Allowed users to create and customize their profiles. Users can upload avatars, bios, and personal information.
- Implemented a feature for users to like posts, display the number of likes for each post, and update likes in real-time.
- Enabled users to create new posts, upload images, add descriptive text.

Deployment & Infrastructure:

- Connected to a MongoDB database using a configuration file, ensuring a modular and maintainable codebase.
- Set up **CORS** for handling cross-origin requests, ensuring frontend-backend communication.

Weather App - https://github.com/chengeden/weather-app

Wold Clock - https://github.com/chengeden/world-clock

Personal Website - https://github.com/chengeden/portfolio

Education

JR Academy (Bootcamp) - Sydney, NSW

Full-stack Program | Mar 2022 - Nov 2022

University of Sydney - Sydney, NSW

- Master of Information Technology | Mar 2013 Dec 2013
- Major in Software Engineering

RMIT University - Melbourne, VIC

- Bachelor of Information Technology | Mar 2010 Dec 2012
- Major in Application Programming, Minor in Multimedia Design